<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>J. An&#39;s Blog</title>
  
  
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://j-an.org/blog/"/>
  <updated>2020-12-20T19:21:07.970Z</updated>
  <id>https://j-an.org/blog/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>J. An</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>In-depth Study</title>
    <link href="https://j-an.org/blog/indepth-study/"/>
    <id>https://j-an.org/blog/indepth-study/</id>
    <published>2020-12-01T15:14:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-20T19:21:07.970Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The in-depth study documentation for the graduate level course COMS 6998: Cloud Computing &amp;amp; Big Data taken in Fall 2020 @ Columbia. Topics include the ELK Stack, Kafka (w/ AWS MSK) and more to be determined.
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Decode the Secrets Behind Recommender Systems</title>
    <link href="https://j-an.org/blog/matrix-factorization/"/>
    <id>https://j-an.org/blog/matrix-factorization/</id>
    <published>2020-09-13T16:11:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T19:06:44.921Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;This is a blog about the secrets behind one kind of recommender systems that using the Matrix Factorization technique to generate new data based on the user behaivor data already provided. A typical use scenario is recommending new movies or shows that the user haven’t watched but may like according to the movies or shows the user already rated. This blog will go thorugh the theory behind this technique and several interesting use cases are also provided.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="ML" scheme="https://j-an.org/blog/tags/ML/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>NLP Topics</title>
    <link href="https://j-an.org/blog/nlp-topics/"/>
    <id>https://j-an.org/blog/nlp-topics/</id>
    <published>2020-08-02T14:00:14.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-08-02T14:44:28.749Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Natural language processing is a subfield of linguistics, computer science, information engineering, and artificial intelligence concerned with the interactions between computers and human languages, in particular how to program computers to process and analyze large amounts of natural language data. This article collects a bunch of topics in this area and gives a brief explanation for each of them. The original layout is provided by Prof. Daniel Bauer in his NLP class. I editied it and tried to enrich the content for further study use.
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="ML" scheme="https://j-an.org/blog/tags/ML/"/>
    
      <category term="NLP" scheme="https://j-an.org/blog/tags/NLP/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Load Third-party Netflix Subtitles</title>
    <link href="https://j-an.org/blog/netflix-subtitles/"/>
    <id>https://j-an.org/blog/netflix-subtitles/</id>
    <published>2020-08-02T04:32:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-12-01T18:58:26.117Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;As a Netflix subscriber, you may find some shows or movies are geo-restricted in the specific countires/regions. After spending a bunch of time selecting a usable VPN to trick Netflix into thinking you are in the region the content is avaliable, you may then face another problem: the subtitle for the show in this region only supports the local language and you may not understand it (i.e., the show &lt;em&gt;Solitary Gourmet&lt;/em&gt; only provides Janpanese subtitle in Janpan). Well, don’t be panic, here is a way to help you load any third-party subtitle when watching netflix and no plugins needed.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Netflix" scheme="https://j-an.org/blog/tags/Netflix/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World &amp; LaTeX Testing</title>
    <link href="https://j-an.org/blog/hello-world/"/>
    <id>https://j-an.org/blog/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2020-08-02T04:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-08-02T18:14:02.481Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Welcome to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/&quot;&gt;Hexo&lt;/a&gt;! This is your very first post. Check &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html&quot;&gt;troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; or you can ask me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. $\LaTeX$&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
      <category term="Hexo" scheme="https://j-an.org/blog/tags/Hexo/"/>
    
      <category term="$\LaTeX$" scheme="https://j-an.org/blog/tags/LaTeX/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
